[The Shinsengumi has 45 articles strictly enforced
by the laws of the "Kyukuchu Hatto."]
[Hijikata, the man who created those laws, couldn't
possibly...?! And "the man" who returned is...?!]
[Shinsengumi Headquarters]
(隊士)聞いたか？
近々 あの人が仕事を終えて➡
Did you hear? It seems that guy is returning
to Edo after finishing his job.
江戸に戻ってくるらしいよ｡
It's Sensei, right? His baggage
arrived already.
(隊士)先生だろ｡
荷物のほうが先に届いてるよ｡
あの人が仕入れた 新型武器｡
The new weapons he got are inside.
I heard he also picked up some
good quality swords,
(隊士)なんか 上物の刀剣とかも
手に入れてきたらしくて➡
so the top members are scrambling.
上の連中が取り合ってるって話だ｡
(隊士)いいな！ ｵﾚも欲しいな｡
おﾆｭｰの刀…｡
They're really lucky.
I want a new sword, too.
Ah-hem.
(山崎)ｺﾞﾎﾝ ｺﾞﾎﾝ！
(隊士)あっ！ 山崎さん｡
Ah, Yamazaki-san.
あぁ～っ！
ひょっとして その刀は…｡
Ah! Could that sword be...
(隊士)長船 Ｍ-Ⅱ!?
...an Osafune Mark II?!
[Note: Parody of Bizen Osafune, a famous sword.]
(隊士)すげぇ！
ﾌﾞﾗﾝﾄﾞもんだ｡ かっけぇ!!
That's great! It's got the brand
name on it. So cool!
(山崎)あの… ｵﾚ 別に
自慢しにきたわけじゃないから｡
Well, it's not like I came
here to show it off.
たまたま 通っただけだから｡
たまたま…｡
(隊士)いいな！
I just happened to pass by. By chance...
I'm jealous.
ちょっと… ちょっとだけ
素振りさせてください！
Just a little... Please let
me try a practice swing!
(山崎)あぁ もちろん いいよ｡
Ah, of course you can.
(隊士)あぁ やっぱ 違うわ
ﾌﾞﾗﾝﾄﾞもんは！
Wow! I can really feel that
brand-name difference!
Additionally, it's waterproof. I don't
want to brag, you know...
しかも 防水加工らしいよ なんか｡
別に自慢してるわけじゃないけど｡
(沖田)お～い
何を騒いでるんでぇ？ ﾃﾒｴら｡
Hey, what are you guys making
such a fuss about?
(隊士)あ… 沖田隊長｡
Ah, Captain Okita.
Look at Yamazaki-san's sword...
(隊士)見てくださいよ！
山崎さんの… おっ!?
Huh?
(隊士)あぁ～っ！ その刀は!!
(隊士)菊一文字 ＲＸｰ78!!
That sword is a...
Kikuichimonji RX-78!
[Note: It's rumored the historical Soji Okita
used a sword named Kikuichimonji.]
(隊士)ﾃﾞｼﾞﾀﾙﾐｭｰｼﾞｯｸﾌﾟﾚｰﾔｰ搭載で➡
It has a built-in digital music player with
a maximum playing time of 124 hours!
連続再生時間 最大124時間にも
およぶ大業物 菊一文字 ＲＸｰ78｡
It's the Kikuichimonji RX-78!
It costs twice as much as the Osafune!
(隊士)長船の倍の値段だよ！
The swords at the captain's
level are really something!
さすが 隊長格は
さしてる得物が違う！
(沖田)あぁ これ
そんな すごいんだ｡
Hmm... Is this sword that great?
適当にもらってきたから
知らなかった｡
I just picked it up without thinking,
so I didn't realize that.
あれ？ その棒…
山崎 なに？ 買ったの？
Huh?
What's that stick? Yamazaki... What
is that? Did you buy that?
その腐りかけの棒｡
It almost looks rusted.
(隊士)隊長！ ちょっとだけ
素振りさせてください!!
Captain, please let me try a
few practice swings for a bit!
(隊士)うぉ～！
やっぱ 違うわ 一級品は｡
Wow! This first-class stuff
is really amazing!
音が 全然 違うもん！
重低音がすごい!!
It sounds completely different!
The deep bass is amazing!
(近藤)おい！ なんだ？
朝から騒々しいぞ｡
Hey, what's going on? Why
is it so noisy this morning?
(隊士)局長 すみません｡ あの…｡
Chief! I'm sorry. Well...
あぁ～っ！ その刀は…｡
That sword is...
虎鉄 ＺｰⅡ…
ﾃﾞｼﾞﾀﾙ音楽機器としての➡
The Kotetsu Z-Second.
[Note: Kotetsu Nagasone was a famous swordsmith. The historical Isami Kondo was said to own a fake Kotetsu sword.]
Not only does it have digital
music equipment,
機能はもちろん 柄に特殊金具を
装着させることにより➡
but it also has a special metal attachment on
the end that can be used as a floor cleaner!
部屋を掃除する
ｺﾛｺﾛとしても使える大業物！
It costs three times as much
as the Kikuichimonji! Cool!
菊一文字の３倍はするぜ｡ すげぇ｡
(近藤)ｵﾒｴら そんな安い刀
使ってんのか？ 刀は 武士の魂だ｡
You guys are using such cheap swords?
A sword is a samurai's soul.
そんなﾋｮﾛいもん 使ってるなんざ
ﾃﾒｴらの魂もしれたもんだな｡
If you use such shabby swords, it'll
reveal the true nature of your soul.
Kondo-san, you're great! We
won't ever be equal to you.
(沖田)すげぇや 近藤さん｡
敵わねえや｡
ｵﾚたちもがんばって あれくらいの
業物 持てるようにならねえとな｡
We should work harder and hope to some
day own stuff on your kind of level.
近藤さん… ちょっとだけ➡
Kondo-san, can I try some practice
swings for a moment?
素振りさせてもらっても
いいですかね？
Ah, go right ahead.
あぁ 別にいいけど｡
(近藤)あぁ～っ!! 虎鉄!!
There!
Kotetsu!
(沖田)あ すいやせん｡
Ah, I'm sorry. I thought a sword like this
could cut through rock, but it failed.
これなら 岩も両断できると
思ったんですけど ﾀﾞﾒでした｡
(近藤)ｵﾒｴ!! 絶対 わざとだろ！
You! You definitely did that on purpose!
ｵﾚの虎鉄ちゃんに
嫉妬して… 嫉妬して～！
You were jealous of my Kotetsu-chan...
You were jealous!
["Rules Are Made to be Broken"]
I'm not going to say a sword
is a samurai's soul.
《土方:刀が武士の魂なんぞと
のたまうつもりは ねえ｡
Besides, I don't think the level of the
sword one carries raises his status.
まして 刀の格式の高さが➡
自分の位も高めてくれるとも
思っちゃいねえ｡
For me, a sword is just a sword.
ｵﾚにとっては 刀は 刀でしかない｡
And that's the most important
thing to me.
いや それこそが ｵﾚにとって
もっとも必要なものだった｡
Most important of all is a sword that can
break through the enemy's blade.
なによりもまず ｵﾚに必要なのは➡
敵の白刃を
切り抜けるための刀だった》
It seems you're overdoing
it as rashly as ever.
(刀工)あいかわらず
ﾑﾁｬしてるようだな｡
A sword can be used again
after it's been mended,
刀は鍛えりゃ また使えるが
人間は そうはいかんぞ｡
but humans don't work that way.
(土方)人間も 折れなきゃ
また 叩きあげられるだろ｡
As long as a human doesn't
break, he can recover, right?
If you keep fighting in such a way that
damages your sword so much,
(刀工)刀が こんなざまに
なっちまう戦い方してたら➡
you'll end up being broken in two
pretty soon. That's what I meant.
そのうち ｵﾒｴさんも
ﾎﾟｯｷﾘ折れる と言っておる｡
(土方)いい刀だな｡
This looks like a good sword.
じいさん ｵﾚのが直るまで
ｺｲﾂを使わせてくれ｡
Old man, until mine is repaired,
let me borrow this.
(刀工)ｿｲﾂは ﾀﾞﾒだ｡
You can't use that one.
ｿｲﾂは ちょっと
いわくつきの刀でな｡
That sword comes with a story behind it.
なんだよ？ 音楽 聴けたり
ｺﾛｺﾛになったりするっつうのか？
What? You mean I can listen to music with
it or it can be used as a floor cleaner?
(刀工)恐ろしく斬れることには
ちげぇねえ｡ だが…｡
There's no question that sword
is terribly sharp. However...
It's cursed.
(刀工)呪われとる｡
(土方)呪い？ 冗談 よせよ｡
Cursed? You've got to be kidding me.
(刀工)並の使い手じゃ 逆に刀に
魂を食われちまうじゃろうて｡
An ordinary sword user will be consumed
by the soul of that sword.
ｵﾒｴさんじゃ 使いこなせまい｡
You won't able to handle it.
...Will you listen to my old
story for a moment?
少し 昔話に
つきあってもらえるか？
It's a tragic tale of a reincarnated
demonic sword...
その妖刀にまつわる
悲しき輪廻の物語を…｡
《土方:聞かなかった｡
じじいの話は 総じて長い｡
But I didn't listen to it.
In general, old men's stories tend to
be long. I don't have time for that.
ｵﾚには そんなことに
つきあっているﾋﾏはない｡
Whether its price is high or low, whether
it can be used to listen to music,
値が張ろうが張るまいが
音楽が聴けようが聴けまいが➡
or whether the sword is cursed,
it doesn't matter to me.
妖刀だろうが なんだろうが
ｵﾚには関係ない》
(浪士)真選組 副長
土方 十四郎殿とお見受けする｡
You must be Shinsengumi Vice-Chief
Toshiro Hijikata-dono.
Although you're a samurai, you've
sided with the Amanto for perks!
(浪士)侍でありながら 天人に
迎合し 甘い汁をすする売国奴が！
You're a traitor! We, the advanced
party of the Anti-Foreigner Faction,
我ら 攘夷の尖兵が 天誅を下さん｡
are here to bring punishment
from heaven!
This is a chance to test it out.
《さっそく 試し斬りの機会だ｡
見せてもらおう 妖刀の切れ味》
Let me see how this cursed
demonic sword works.
Here we go!
いくぜ～っ！
すみませ～ん!!
I'm sorry!
《あれ？ なんだ!? これ！
Huh? What's this...?
な… 何 やってんだ？ ｵﾚ｡
Wh-What am I doing? My body
is moving on its own...
か… 体が勝手に 口が勝手に…》
My mouth is moving on its own...
I'm sorry! My life! Please spare me!
すみませ～ん！ 命だけは…
命だけは勘弁してください!!
I'll lick anything, even the
soles of your sandals!
草履の裏でも なんでも
なめますんで！
(浪士たち)ｷﾞｬﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
(浪士)誰だ？ このﾍﾀﾚは！
Who's this pathetic guy?!
(浪士)あの土方 十四郎が！
あの 鬼の副長と恐れられる男が！
That's Toshiro Hijikata!
The man who is feared as the Demon
Vice-Chief! How miserable!
なんたるｻﾞﾏだ！ ﾌﾞﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
《ど ど ど… どういうことだ！
Wh-Wh-What's wrong with me?!
My body doesn't respond at all!
体が まったく
いうことをきかねえ！》
An ordinary sword user will be consumed
by the soul of that sword.
((並の使い手じゃ 逆に刀に
魂を食われちまうじゃろうて…))
《まさか… ｺｲﾂ！
Don't tell me... This...?!
妖刀の呪いで ｵﾚは こんなことに
なっちまってるっていうのか!?
Why is the demonic sword's curse making
me act this way?! That's ridiculous...!
んな ﾊﾞｶな話が…》
(浪士)なんだか知らねえが
今まで さんざん世話になった分➡
I don't know what's going on,
but we'll be paying you back for
everything you did to us before!
きっちり返して
もらおうじゃねえか！
えぇ おい！ 草履の裏でも
なめんだろ？ なめてみろや！
You just said you would lick the soles
of our sandals, didn't you?!
Then lick it!
ﾃ… ﾃﾒｴ…｡
Y-You bastard!
《妖刀だかなんだか知らねえが➡
It may be a cursed sword or whatever,
but... I... Ugh... won't...!
ｵﾚが… ぐっ…
これぐらいで…っ！》
あの これくらいで
ﾎﾝﾄ勘弁してください｡
Um... Please forgive
me by accepting this.
(土方)3,000円あるんで
あの Suicaは勘弁してください｡
I have 3,000 yen.
But please don't take my Suica, because
I won't be able to go home without it.
[Note: Suica is a rechargeable IC card used
as a fare card on train lines in Japan.]
家 帰れなくなるんで…｡
(浪士)びっくりさせんじゃねえ！
Don't screw with us!
(浪士)なんだ ｺｲﾂ！
ｺﾛｺﾛ変わりやがって！
What's with this guy?!
He's flip-flopping his personality!
つうか 大の大人が 3,000円って
どういうことだぁ！
Anyway, why does an adult like
you have only 3,000 yen?!
《ﾀﾞﾒだ… 完全に
ｲｶれちまってる…｡
This is bad... There's something
totally wrong with me...
I'm a goner...
やられる… このままじゃ…｡
As things are...
やられ…》
I'll be finished...
Hey!
(伊東)おい！
《土方:見慣れた制服…
見慣れた太刀筋…｡
A familiar uniform.
A familiar stance.
だが そのﾂﾗは…》
But his face is...
(伊東)真選組隊士が襲われている
と思い 駆けつけてみれば…｡
I just saw a member of the Shinsengumi
being attacked, so I rushed over here...
(伊東)こんなところで
何をやっているんだ？
What are you doing in a place like this,
(伊東)土方君｡
(土方)お… お前は…｡
Hijikata-kun?
You're...
(近藤)伊東 鴨太郎君の
帰陣を祝して 乾杯！
A toast to Kamotaro Ito-kun's
return. Cheers!
(一同)乾杯！
Cheers!
いや～ 伊東先生｡ 今回は
本当に ご苦労さまでした｡
Well, Ito Sensei, you did
a good job this time.
しかし あれだけの武器…｡
But that many weapons...
よくも あの幕府のｹﾁどもが
財布のﾋﾓを解いてくれましたなぁ｡
I wonder how you got those stingy people in
the government to loosen their purse strings!
近藤さん｡ ｹﾁとは
別の見方をすれば➡
Kondo-san, being stingy means being shrewd
enough to profit from a different viewpoint.
利に聡いということだ｡ ならば
ﾎﾞｸらへの出資によって生まれる➡
All you have to do is just explain that the government
will profit by making expenditures on us...
幕府の利を説いてやれば
いいだけのこと…｡
もっとも 近藤さんの言うとおり
地上で這いつくばって生きる➡
Though, just as you say, Kondo-san,
they're pertinacious people who don't care
about our hardships and groveling.
我々の苦しみなど
意にも介さぬ頑冥な連中だ｡
日々 強大化していく
攘夷志士の脅威を➡
It wasn't easy for me to explain it to them,
in a way they could easily understand.
わかりやすく説明するのも
ひと苦労だったがね｡
ｱﾊｯ！ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
違いない！ 違いないよ｡
That's right! That's absolutely right!
ｶﾞﾝﾒｲだよね ｱｲﾂら｡ ﾎﾝﾄ ｶﾞﾝﾒｲ｡
They're pertinacious! They really are!
近藤さん 頑冥って何ですか？
Kondo-san, what does
pertinacious mean?
(近藤)うるさいよ お前は！
子供は黙ってなさい！
You shut up! Kids should be quiet!
(伊東)近藤さん
あのような者たちが➡
Kondo-san, if people like them stay at
the top, this country will be ruined.
上にあっては いずれ
この国は滅ぶだろう｡
我々は こんなところで➡
We can't stay in a smoldering
place like this.
いつまでも
くすぶっていてはいけない｡
進まなければならない！
We have to move forward! We must
work toward a higher goal!
ﾎﾞｸらは もっと上を目指して
邁進しなければいけない！
And we'll eventually become like the swords,
the keystones of this country.
そして いずれは
国の中枢を担う剣となり➡
この混迷する国を救うことこそが
この時代の武士として➡
I believe that saving this confused country is
the mission for those of us born as samurai.
生まれた者の使命だと
ﾎﾞｸは考える！
(伊東)そのためならば ﾎﾞｸはｷﾐに➡
For that, I wouldn't mind
giving my life to you!
この命を捧げても
構わないと思っている！
近藤さん 一緒に頑張りましょう！
Kondo-san, let's work hard together!
うむ みんな ｶﾞﾝﾒｲに頑張るぞ！
Right. Everyone, let's work
hard pertinacious!
(伊東)いや 頑冥の使い方
間違ってます…｡
No, you're using "pertinacious"
the wrong way.
(隊士)また始まったよ
伊東さんのご高説が！
Ito-san has started expressing
his valuable opinions again.
局長も 先生なんて呼んでんだぜ！
Even the Chief calls him "Sensei."
ｳﾁに入って
１年あまりの新参者を｡
He's just a newcomer who
joined us only a year ago.
(隊士)向こうも 参謀なんて
新しいﾎﾟｽﾄもらって➡
I wonder if he's getting so full of himself
調子のってんじゃねえの？
because he was just assigned the title of advisor.
I'm not blaming him.
(隊士)無理もねえよ！
頭は ｷﾚるわ 仕事はできるわ➡
He's intelligent, really good at his job and
is fully proficient in Hokuto Itto Ryu.
[Note: The Hokuto Itto Ryu is a northern sword style.]
おまけに北斗一刀流免許皆伝だぜ｡
同じ頭が ｷﾚるのでも
副長は あくまで戦術家としてだ｡
Vice-Chief is also intelligent, but he's
really only a battle strategist.
政治方面やれるのは
あの人しかいねえ｡
So Ito-san's the only person who
can manage political matters.
そりゃ 局長も重宝するはずだ！
No wonder he is a great help to the chief.
伊東さん 今まで
ほとんど屯所にいなかったが➡
Ito-san has hardly ever been in the headquarters...
but it might be about time...
そろそろくるかもな｡
何が？
For what?
(隊士)ｵﾚ 伊東さんと土方さんが➡
I've never seen Ito-san and Hijikata-san talk
about each other, only about their jobs.
仕事以外でしゃべってんの
見たことねえもん！
♪♪～
(伊東)土方君…
ｷﾐに聞きたいことがあった｡
Hijikata-kun, I have something
to ask you.
(土方)奇遇だな… ｵﾚもだ｡
What a coincidence... me, too.
お前は ｵﾚのこと嫌いだろう？
ｷﾐは ﾎﾞｸのこと嫌いだろう？
You hate me,
don't you?
近藤さんに気に入られ➡
Because I'm Kondo-san's favorite,
and although I'm a newcomer,
新参者でありながら
ｷﾐの地位を脅かすまで➡
I'm rising to fame so fast
that it threatens you.
ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞ出世するﾎﾞｸが
目障りで しかたないんだろ？
I bet I'm an eyesore to you, right?
それは ｱﾝﾀだ…｡
さっさと出世したいのに➡
That's what you think? You want to advance
in your career, but I'm higher than you.
上にいつまでも
どっかり座ってる➡
ｵﾚが目障りで しかたあるめえよ｡
I bet I'm an eyesore to you, right?
(伊東)ﾌｯ… 邪推だ 土方君｡
ﾎﾞｸは そんなこと考えちゃいない｡
It's a groundless suspicion, Hijikata-kun.
I don't think about that kind of thing.
(土方)よかったな…
お互い誤解が解けたらしい｡
That's good. It seems we have cleared
up any misunderstandings.
目障りなんて…｡
An eyesore...
It's even more than that.
そんな かわいいもんじゃないさ｡
(２人)いずれ殺してやるよ…｡
Some time in the future, I'll kill you.
Toshi...
(近藤)ﾄｼ 伊東先生から聞いたぞ！
I heard about you from Ito Sensei.
災難だったな…
体のほうは大丈夫か？
That was a stroke of bad
luck. How's your injury?
ﾄｼ… ｵﾚたちは 武士なんぞと
名乗っちゃいるが➡
Toshi...
Although we call ourselves samurai,
ただの芋の集まりにすぎん｡
we're really just a bunch of country boys.
そんなｵﾚたちが 死地において➡
[Kyukuchu Hatto]
Even though that's what we
are, when facing death,
武士よりもなお 武士らしく
己を奮い立たせられるのは➡
we're able to act more like
samurai than real samurai.
お前が生み出した厳しい掟➡
It was because of the Kyokuchu Hatto,
局中法度の存在の
おかげに他ならん｡
the strict laws you created,
that we can be like that.
It has 45 articles, encompassing everything
from daily behavior to manners,
45箇条からなる
日常の細かい所作から礼儀➡
戦での覚悟までを説き
厳しく律する法度➡
and even battle preparation.
These are the strict laws that govern us.
これを一つでも犯せば 即切腹｡
If you break any one of those laws,
you'll have to commit seppuku.
そこには お前の理想とする
侍像が つまっている…｡
That's your image of the ideal samurai.
ｵﾚたちは皆 それに賛同した｡
わかるか ﾄｼ？
We all agree.
Do you understand, Toshi?
お前は ﾔﾂらにとって
理想の武士のうつし身だ｡
You're the ideal samurai
model for everyone.
みんな お前を手本としている｡
みんな お前を見ている｡
Everyone models himself after
you. Everyone watches you.
ｵﾚが言えた義理じゃねえが➡
I'm not in a position to say this, but don't do
anything to betray the way of the samurai.
士道に背くような真似を
してくれるなよ…｡
(土方)たいした野郎だ…｡
...He's quite a guy.
あっという間に広まっちまったよ
ｵﾚの醜態…｡
As quick as a flash, news of my
shameful behavior has spread.
まぁ 野郎にとっては➡
Well, for him, it's the perfect opportunity
to defeat me and rise up the ladder.
ｵﾚを蹴落として のし上がる
絶好の好機だからな｡
ﾄｼ そんな言い方はやめろ！
Toshi, stop talking that way. Ito Sensei is
thinking about the spirit of the group...
伊東先生は隊内の士気を思って…｡
(土方)先生と呼ぶのは
やめろと言ったはずだ｡
I already told you to stop
calling him "Sensei."
近藤さん… ｱﾝﾀ
局長の座を ﾔﾂに譲るつもりか？
Kondo-san, are you going to give
your position of Chief to him?
そうじゃなけりゃ ｱﾝﾀとｱｲﾂ➡
If that's not the case,
are you going to share your position as
head of the Shinsengumi with him?
２人で真選組の頭やるって
腹なのかね…｡
隊士の連中が
ｱｲﾂの扱いに戸惑っているのを➡
Need I remind you that members are
unsure about how to treat him.
知らぬわけじゃあるまい｡
ともに入隊してきた
同門の者の他 数名が➡
His former colleagues, who entered at
the same time, are already his allies.
すでに ﾔﾂに与しているほどだ…｡
伊東先生が 真選組を
乗っ取るつもりだとでも？
Are you saying that Ito Sensei is trying
to take over the Shinsengumi?
さあな… だが ﾔﾂが
異例の出世を遂げる以前から➡
Who knows?
But ever since he got here he's done nothing
but gather allies and influence.
ｱﾝﾀと同等… それ以上の
振る舞いをしているのは確かだよ｡
...It's obvious he's up to something.
ﾔﾂは 今の自分に
増長しているわけでも➡
He's not as powerful as he wants
to be and he's not satisfied.
満足しているわけでもねえ｡
Kondo-san... If a snake has two heads...
近藤さん… 頭が二つあるﾍﾋﾞは
一方の頭が 腐って落ちるか➡
...one either has to rot and fall off or the
ensuing feud will split the body in two.
反目して 真っ二つに
体を引きさいちまうか➡
どちらかだよ｡
ｵﾚは 伊東先生は
真選組に必要な男だと思っている｡
I believe that Ito Sensei is a crucial
man for the Shinsengumi.
Hey, Toshi, we're not doing this
to ensure your own position.
ﾄｼよ… ｵﾚたちゃ
ﾃﾒｴの地位を護るために➡
こんなことを やっちゃいまいよ｡
We're doing this to protect Edo and
to stick to the ways of the samurai.
江戸を護るため
士道を通すためだ｡
そのための知恵なら
誰にでも 教えを請う｡
To get that wisdom, I'll ask for
anyone who can teach it.
教えを請うた者を 先生と呼ぶのは
当然の理だ｡
It's natural to call the person
who teaches us "Sensei."
それを 家来のように
扱えというのなら ｵﾚは断る｡
If you ask me to treat him
like a follower, I'll refuse.
ｵﾚは 一度として お前たちを
家来だと思ったことはねえ｡
I've never thought of you
guys as my followers.
士道の名の下
ｵﾚたちは 五分の仲間だ｡
As for the way of the samurai,
we're on equal footing.
Kondo-san, you don't
understand anything.
近藤さん… ｱﾝﾀ なんにも
わかっちゃいねえ｡
Pretty words won't help manage
the organization...!
きれいごとだけじゃ
組織は動かね…！
Toshi!
(近藤)ﾄｼｰｯ!?
Pretty Girl Samurai, Tomoe 5000 is here!
[Note: Parody of Sailor Moon]
(ﾄﾓｴ)美少女侍 ﾄﾓｴ5000 見参！
しまった～！ もう 始まってる！
録画予約すんの 忘れてた！
Damn it! It's already started! I forgot
to record it! Tomoe-chan!
ﾄﾓｴちゃ～ん！ …はっ！
また 体が勝手に…｡
My body...again...
What am I watching?!
《なんつ～もん
見てるんだ ｵﾚは！》
Punishment is complete.
(隊士)おいおい 聞いたか？
副長の話｡
(隊士)何？
Hey, hey, did you hear
about the Vice-Chief?
Hear what?
(隊士)なんか この間 副長が
浪士たちに➡
The Vice-Chief was attacked by Anti-Foreigner
Faction ronin the other day.
襲撃を受けたところを 伊東さんに
助けられたらしいんだが➡
He was saved by Ito-san. But
you probably won't believe it.
聞いて びっくりだぜ｡
The Vice-Chief knelt, bowed
and begged for his life.
副長 土下座して 助けてくれって
泣きついたらしいぜ｡
いやいや そりゃないよ｡
It's impossible that something
like that could happen.
He would rather die than
do something like that.
そんな真似するくらいなら
あの人は 死ぬっつぅの｡
鬼の副長だよ？ 鬼の｡
He's the demon Vice-Chief.
The "demon."
(隊士)いや ｵﾚも聞いたぜ｡
But I heard it, too.
Hey, hey, cut it out already.
(隊士)おいおい
そのへんにしとけよ｡
If this conversation is overheard,
we'll be in trouble.
こんな話してるの聞かれたら
ことだぜ｡
It's against the Kyokuchu Hatto
rules to pass JUMP around.
ただでさえ ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣回し読みは
局中法度違反なんだぜ｡
"No reading of manga, except for MAGAZINE,
allowed in the headquarters."
[Note: MAGAZINE refers to "Weekly Shonen
MAGAZINE, a rival of Shonen JUMP.]
｢まがじん｣以外のﾏﾝｶﾞ
局内で読むことなかれ…｡
こんなところ見られたら
切腹もんだ｡
If someone sees us, we'll
have to commit seppuku.
あの人 ｢まがじん｣派だからね｡
(土方)ちょっと貸して｡
Hijikata prefers MAGAZINE.
Let me see that.
しかも ひと昔前の ﾔﾝｷｰﾏﾝｶﾞ｡
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣派は つらいぜ｡
Moreover, he liked yankee manga a decade
ago. It's hard for us JUMP fans.
[Note: Yankee manga is a genre
where bad boys fight others.]
ん？ ふ… 副長！ いつの間に!?
V-Vice-Chief! Wh-When did you...?!
違うんです！ これは… あの…
あれ！ 本の厚さが似てるんで➡
No, that's like nothing... That's...uh!
The thickness of the book is about the
same...so I bought it by mistake!
間違って買ってきちゃって！
Hey!
(土方)おい｡
は… はい！
Yes, sir!
"To Love-Ru" is really great.
[Note: "ToLoveる" is a manga in JUMP.]
『To LOVEる』って
超おもしろいよね｡
I'm going to buy the manga.
(土方)単行本 買ってこよっと｡
"To-To-To Love-Ru?" Is
that the Vice-Chief?!
と… 『To LOVEる』？ あの副長が!?
For argument's sake, "Boys be…"
[Note: "Boys be…" is a manga in
Weekly Shonen MAGAZINE.]
百歩譲って 『BOYS BE…』だろ｡
[MEETING ROOM]
(土方)最近は 浪士たちによる
襲撃も増えている｡
These days, attacks by Anti-Foreigner
Faction ronin have increased.
So, make sure not to go off on your own.
くれぐれも
単独行動は避けるように｡
(隊士たち)はい！
Yes, sir!
Then, I'll assign today's
shift. Squad one is…
(土方)それでは 今日の当番を
[TEL]
割り振る｡ 一番隊は…｡
(隊士)やべっ！ ｹｰﾀｲが！
[TEL]
Damn it! My cell phone...!
You idiot!
(隊士)ﾊﾞｶ ｵﾒｴ！ 会議中に
ｹｰﾀｲ鳴らしたﾔﾂは➡
If your cell phone rings during a meeting,
you'll have to commit seppuku
according to the Kyukuchu Hatto.
局中法度で切腹だぞ！
ひいっ！
Hijikata-san! Nothing… I… My wife
is in labor, so she called me…
(隊士)土方さん！ 違うんです！
ｵﾚ… 嫁さんが
産気づいてて 連絡を…｡
[Note: The Pretty Cure (a magical
girl series) song is playing.]
(着信ﾒﾛﾃﾞｨ)
もしもし 土方ですけど… はい
今ですか？ 全然 大丈夫です｡
Hello, this is Hijikata…
Yes…right now? No problem.
え？ 今回の限定版ＤＶＤＢＯＸは
ﾌｨｷﾞｭｱ特典つきですか…｡
Huh? The limited-edition DVD
BOX comes with a figurine?
じゃあ 保存用とあれで
二つ 用意してください｡
Well, then…one to save, and one for
that… I'll need a total of two sets.
(浪士)ぐっ…！
Hey! Spit it out! I'm asking you
where your headquarters is!
(隊士)おらぁ！ 吐きやがれ！
ｵﾒｴらの拠点は
どこだって聞いてんだよ！
(浪士)誰が 仲間を売るものか！
殺すがいい！
I won't sell out my own
comrades! Kill me!
恥をさらすくらいなら
武士らしく 死んでくれるわ！
I'd rather die like a samurai
than shame myself!
おいおい ここへ来て
死ぬことなんて➡
Hey, hey! Do you really think you
can die in a place like this?
できると思ってんの？ ﾋﾋﾋ！
お前は この先ずっと➡
We'll make you feel like you’re in a
hell worse than death from now on.
死よりも苦しい地獄を
味わうことになるんだよ！
副長！ いっちょ
もんだってください！
Vice-Chief!
Work him over! Please.
よろしくお願いします｡
お前たちは 出ていけ｡
Get out of here, you guys.
へ… へい｡
Y-Yes.
He's a really scary guy…
おっかね～ お人だ｡
副長が 直々に手を下すときは➡
When the Vice-Chief works a
guy over with his own hands,
決まって
拷問部屋は静まりかえる｡
the interrogation room becomes
completely silent.
だが ５分後には
どんな 肝の座ったﾔﾂも➡
However, five minutes later,
even the bravest men start crying
and spit out everything.
泣き叫び
すべてを吐いちまうのさ｡
ﾌｯ… ﾌﾌﾌ…｡
いったい 何が
行われてるというんですか!?
Wh-What's going on inside?
覗いてみろ｡
この世の地獄が見えるぜ｡
Just take a peek. You'll see hell on earth.
What? Is there anyone you like?
なに？ 好きな人とかいるの？
(浪士)いや 別にいないけど｡
Not really. I don't have anyone.
なんだよ！ ｵﾚも言ったんだから
お前も言えよな～！
Come on! I already told you,
so it’s your turn to tell me.
ずりぃ！ ずりぃよ！ ﾊﾒたな!?
ﾊﾒたろ！ お前も吐けよ！
It's not fair! Not fair! You lied to me,
didn't you?! You did! You tell me!
わかった！
わかったって！ 吐くよ！
All right! I'll tell you then! But don't
tell anyone! It's a secret.
でも 誰にも言うなよ！
内緒だかんな！
さ～て それは どうかな？
Well, I don't know about that.
(土方)あ やべ！ ｾﾝｺｰどもが
見回りにきた！ ﾀﾊﾞｺ 消せ！
Oh, damn it! The teachers are on
patrol. Put out the cigarettes!
(２人)…修学旅行？
Is this a school trip or something?
(土方)てな具合だ｡
…That's how it goes.
After I got this sword,
everything went wrong.
(土方)すべては 刀を手に
入れてからおかしくなっちまった｡
どうやら ｵﾚはﾎﾝﾄに
ｺｲﾂに呪われちまったらしい｡
It looks like I’m really cursed.
(沖田)ﾀﾞﾊﾊﾊｯ…！
だから 言うのやだったんだよ｡
That’s why I didn't want to tell you.
信じてねえだろ お前｡
信じるわきゃないだろ お前｡
You don't believe me, do you?
There's no way you'll believe me.
ふと気づくと 勝手に
別人格と入れ替わってやがる｡
Just like that, I had switched personalities
with someone completely different.
No, that wasn't someone else.
いや
あれは 別人格なんかじゃねえ｡
The weak side inside everyone
gets awakened by this sword.
人が誰しも
持っている ﾍﾀﾚた部分が➡
ｺｲﾂによって目覚め始めてるんだ｡
土方さん ﾍﾀﾚを
刀のせいにしちゃいけねえや｡
Hijikata-san, you can't blame
being weak on the sword.
土方さんは もともとﾍﾀﾚでしょ？
You were weak to begin
with, Hijikata-san.
そうっすよね
ｵﾚなんて元々こんな…｡
That's right; I'm always like this…
あらら
ｺｲﾂは ﾎﾝﾄに調子がおかしいや｡
Oh, my…this is really something strange.
じゃあ んな妖刀 さっさと捨て
ちまえば いいじゃないですかい｡
Then why don't you just throw
away that cursed sword?
I would, If I could. I even find myself carrying
it with me to the toilet and bath.
そいつができれば
苦労しちゃいねえ｡
気がついたら 厠や風呂にまで
持っていっちまう始末だ｡
I can't get rid of it, even if I want to.
はがそうにも はがれねえ｡
And the old man at the swordsmith’s
isn't there anymore.
鍛冶屋のじじいは こんなときに
限っていやがらねえし｡
するってえと なんですかい？
Then are you trying to say…that's the reason
you had a fight with Kondo-san?
近藤さんと
ｹﾝｶしたのも そいつのせいだと？
そうならいいんだがな｡
…I wish I could say that…
土方さん
こんなときに うかうかしてたら➡
Hijikata-san, if you don’t
pay attention this time,
伊東さんに副長の座奪われますぜ｡
Ito-san will take away your
vice-chief position.
(土方)ﾌｯ それどころじゃねえよ｡
No time for that now.
ｵﾚは こんなんなっちまってから➡
Since I became like this, I've already broken
more than ten of the Kyokuchu Hatto rules.
すでに 10を超える
局中法度を犯してる｡
明日にでも 伊東から切腹の
申し渡しがきてもおかしかねえよ｡
If Ito delivers a sentence for seppuku
tomorrow, I wouldn't be surprised.
今のﾍﾀﾚたｵﾚじゃ 呑みかねねえ｡
As I am right now, I wouldn't refuse.
お前も ｵﾚなんかといると
伊東に目をつけられるぞ｡
If you're with me, you'll
attract Ito's attention.
土方さん…
待ってくだせえ 土方さん！
…Hijikata-san…
Wait, Hijikata-san!
焼きそばﾊﾟﾝ買ってこいよ！
Go buy me a Yakisoba pan.
[Note: Yakisoba pan is noodles in a hot dog bun.]
あと ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣もな
もちろんお前の金で｡
And JUMP, too. Of course,
you pay for them.
遅いなぁ ﾄｼのﾔﾂ｡
Toshi is late. It's already past the time.
もうとっくに時間は過ぎている｡
大事な会議だというのに…｡
This is a really important meeting…
Kondo-san.
(伊東)近藤さん いい機会だ｡
This is a good opportunity. I was going
to bring him up for discussion.
ﾎﾞｸは ちょうど彼のことを
議題に出すつもりでいた｡
最近の彼の行動については➡
I think you’ve already heard
about his recent behavior.
すでに諸君も
聞き及んでいるだろう｡
自ら 隊士たちに局中法度という
厳しい規律を課しながら➡
He broke the Kyokuchu Hatto
rules more than ten times.
And yet he created those
rules for the members.
彼は これを破ること十数度｡
(伊東)現に今も 重役会議に
遅刻するという失態を犯している｡
Besides him being late for an
important meeting like this,
これを野放しにしていては
隊士たちに示しがつかない！
If we continue to let him act like this, we won't
be able to control the other members.
先生 待ってくれ！ ﾄｼのことだ
何か 並々ならぬ事情があって…｡
Sensei, hold on. I know Toshi well.
He must have something
exceedingly important…
(伊東)ﾎﾞｸは 今回の件のことだけを
言っているのではない｡
I'm not only talking about
this particular case.
もちろん 彼がこれまで真選組で
どれだけ功績をあげてきたか➡
Of course, I fully understand what he
achieved for the Shinsengumi before.
そのことも重々承知している｡
That's why I want to give
him some candid advice.
だからこそあえて苦言を呈したい｡
真選組の象徴とも
いうべき彼が 法度を軽んずれば➡
If he's the symbol of the Shinsengumi,
and he downplays the rules,
しぜん隊士たちもそれに倣う｡
other members will do the same.
規律を失った群狼は
烏合の衆と成り果てる｡
A pack of wolves that has lost its discipline
will be like sheep without a shepherd.
彼にこそ
厳しい処罰が必要なのだ！
He's the one who deserves
strict punishment!
近藤さん ここは 英断を！
Kondo-san, please make a firm decision!
Hold on! Toshi will definitely…
待ってくれ！ ﾄｼは必ず…｡
(物音)
Hi! I bought your Yakisoba
pan, Okita Senpai!
ちゃ～す！ 焼きそばﾊﾟﾝ
買ってきたっす 沖田先輩！
(土方)すみません！
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣がなかったんで｢まがじん｣｡
I'm sorry, but they didn't have
JUMP, so I got MAGAZINE…
♪♪～
ﾌﾝ｡
ﾌｯ｡
D-Damn it! I was trapped!
《し しまったぁ！ ﾊ ﾊﾒられた》
《ｺｲﾂら… 組んでやがった》
Those guys…were working together!
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
I didn't expect anything
like that, Okita-kun.
That you would be on my
side. What do you desire?
Naturally…the Vice-Chief position.
["Otaku Are Talkative"]
[Hijikata knowingly broke the "Kyokuchu Hatto",
and has been exiled from the Shinsengumi.]
[He becomes a hopeless otaku and visits
the Odd Jobs with "a request."]